Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
Clay.
Clay. help me!
He was hurt.
Dying.
And I couldn't help him.
I just watched him bleed.
Jesus. Clay. Come on. Help me.
Uh...
Clay!
Clay! Clay. what the fuck?
And... time!
I'm afraid your victim
didn't make it. guys.
- Sorry.
- Let's see how other teams did.
Wow. You guys really nailed it. huh?
Really nice work on the bandages too.
I just figured close range
with a clean exit point.
Probably best to apply constant
pressure with a compress.
It would really be more realistic
for us to deal with a high-velocity.
high-impact wound.
like a .223 from an assault rifle.
Those are illegal in California. no?
No. yeah. they are.
Hey. great work. everyone.
Look. I know this can
be a tough exercise.
but it only takes two to five minutes
for someone to bleed out
from a gunshot wound. Right?
Our goal today is to...
A tourniquet would do
fuck-all when a single bullet
from an AR-15 rips open your insides.
So. how about this?
Instead of teaching
us to stop the bleed.
they make it less likely
we'll actually get shot
at our own fucking high school?
Wouldn't that make more sense?
It must be upsetting to go
through that kind of training.
This is when I lose respect for you.
when you ask the most obvious question.
Would you rather I presume
to know how you feel without asking?
Okay. now you're just arguing.
I don't mean to be.
How'd the stop-the-bleed
exercise make you feel?
Helpless.
It's awful. Feeling helpless
is the worst feeling there is.
- Tell me why.
- I mean. isn't that obvious?
Let's say it's not.
Why is feeling helpless. for you.
the worst feeling there is?
Is helping people important to you?
Isn't that important to you?
Very. and sometimes I can't help them.
And what do you do?
Well. I try...
everything I know to try.
I consult with colleagues.
but in the end.
if I can't help a patient.
then I try to find someone who can.
But after all that.
are certain people beyond help?
I hope not.
Do you worry that you're beyond help?
Yeah.
A few sessions ago.
we talked about how you punish yourself.
Do you think you deserve to be punished?
I think I do.
I feel like I've let my friends down
and I'm not there for
them like I should be.
I've been asking
around trying to find him.
Pizza place doesn't know.
So he meets up with Tyler
and then just disappears?
He hasn't been in the neighborhood.
I went and asked around the docks.
I told you not to go down there.
Oh.
You "told me".
You never did say what you were
doing there in the first place.
Tony. my recovery is strong
enough to see some familiar faces.
Forgive me if I'm not a big believer
in people recovering at the moment.
We don't know Tyler slipped.
We don't know for sure what we even saw.
Really? What did it look like to you?
Yeah. but there's been nothing
since. right? Has he done anything?
Said anything weird?
He's Tyler.
He says weird shit all the fucking time.
Should we tell Alex about what we saw?
You think we should tell Alex.
Now I know you're worried.
I believe in Tyler.
I want to.
I made a bunch of messes
I don't know how to clean up.
Hey.
Welcome back.
Welcome back?
Fuck you!
Jesus.
Zach. I...
I don't know what happened.
You mean after you crashed
my car and ditched me.
I don't remember anything.
You gotta believe me.
From before the party.
Justin told me all kinds
of crazy shit happened.
- and I don't remember.
- At some point.
you had to have realized
you crashed my car and
left me for dead. Right?
I swear to God. I don't remember.
Zach.
You know. the crazy thing is...
you didn't even seem scared.
No. your eyes. it was like
you weren't even there.
It was like you were... somebody else.
Right before you drove
my car off the edge
and sent me flying 30 fucking feet.
Zach. I am so sorry.
Don't worry about it. My
lawyer says he can get me off.
He has a lot of practice. He
was Bryce's lawyer.
It's funny. right?
Um. no.
Correct.
None of this is fucking funny anymore.
You are a goddamn
nightmare. so please...
please just stay the
fuck out of my life.
Forever.
I've just... I've lost friends.
I've made enemies.
I need my life to change.
something to. like. wake me up.
He just sat there and
let the dummy bleed out.
Luke. he saw the whole thing.
Said it was fucking creepy.
Oh. Well. maybe he didn't
like the sight of blood.
It's kind of fucked up they're
making us learn that stuff.
I'm just saying. He's this
close to full-blown psycho now.
Well. that wouldn't have anything to do
with you and your boys. would it?
I told you. we're not
messing with him anymore.
We got other ways to
figure out what he's hiding.
What's that supposed to mean?
Just that he's got a lot of friends...
and one of them is
bound to know something.
Well. you'd better
not do anything stupid.
or you're just gonna get
yourself suspended again.
Good thing I'm dating
the school president.
Which means you really
don't want to piss me off.
especially when we're
having so much fun together.
Sit. Mr. Jensen.
Not to be rude. but. like. who are you?
Dean Foundry.
Dean is your name or your title?
Title. I'm the new
dean of discipline. Sit.
Wait.
Dean of which now?
The district feels it
needs a more active role
in monitoring the student body
and managing disruptions to
the learning environment. and...
it seems they're right. judging
from the smashed security cameras
we've been dealing with
for the past two weeks.
Can you account for your whereabouts
between midnight and 7:00 a.m. today?
- I'm guessing I was in bed.
- Guessing?
I was in bed.
- What time did you arrive at school?
- I don't know.
- 9:30 or something.
- Or something?
- 9:30.
- 9:47. actually.
Almost two hours late.
I was in an appointment.
Right. ask my mom.
I already have done.
She wasn't aware of any appointment.
She'll be speaking with you tonight.
Anything you wanna tell
me about the cameras?
Or who might have seen
fit to destroy them?
No. Nothing I want to tell you.
Well. if you think of anything
later. I'm always here.
Now. back to class.
Take good care.
Wait. How...
How did you know that I
got here at exactly 9:47?
I know a lot. Clay.
Get to class.
Hey!
Congrats on the interview.
- Uh. what? What are you talking about?
- Brown.
Uh. the alumni reps
are coming next week.
I saw the schedule on Bolan's desk.
That's gotta be a mistake. I...
Not unless there's another
Clay Jensen around here
I don't know about. which is. like...
One is enough.
But you...
you did apply there. didn't you?
I. uh...
I mean. I guess.
Hi.
I didn't realize the door
under the stairs led anywhere.
- Hi.
- It's quiet down here in the mornings.
I get work done.
I looked through my brother's
stuff like you asked.
The police kept most of it.
but I thought this might
be something to look at.
- Schoolwork?
- A football playbook.
I don't understand
the plays or anything.
but while the coaches taught the plays.
the guys wrote notes to each other.
Monty. Bryce. Diego.
There's. like. two years' worth.
from before and after Bryce died.
Okay. "Es dudoso que...
llover谩 ma帽ana".
What?
Nothing.
See. you're using "que". so
it has to be the subjunctive.
The subjunctive mood can also be used
when expressing a speaker's
feelings about a perceived reality.
"I'm sorry you're cold".
Siento que tengas fr铆o.
Tony. I'm sorry you have to hear
this. You could school us both.
Yes. but it wouldn't be
nearly as entertaining.
May I have your attention. please?
We are currently moving
into a lockdown situation.
Code Red.
This is a hard lockdown.
Staff. please initiate lockdown
procedures immediately.
Students. please do not panic.
and listen closely to this announcement
and the instructions of your teacher.
Seek immediate shelter
in the nearest classroom.
I repeat. This is a Code
Red. Hard lockdown.
Code Red. That's active shooter. right?
Yeah. it's gotta be
another stupid drill.
Okay. everyone listen up. please!
I need some students to help
me barricade the doors.
- You. you. You three. let's go.
- Come on. let's go. Come on.
He. uh. doesn't look like
he was expecting a drill.
- Let's get those lights off.
- What is it?
Tyler's gone.
The rest of you. stop what you're doing
and you need to
shelter under the tables.
Right here.
Tony. hey.
Hey. what is it?
Yeah. what do you know?
What's up with Tyler?
I think he's been buying guns.
Okay. everybody. just
stay down. stay quiet.
Come on. Quicker.
Why can't we do this
bullshit when I have English?
Hey. Justin.
Once everyone's inside. lock
the doors. You know the protocol.
All right. Coach. This
is just a drill. right?
I'll see what I can find out.
Hey. towards the back. in the
showers. Away from the doors.
All right? Y'all stay low.
Hey. man.
You okay?
Code Red means it's real. right?
Hey. check it.
No windows. Cement walls.
And if someone does try and
come in here. we... we handle it.
No one's getting hurt today.
No talking.
Why so concerned?
Your boy Clay bring something
bigger than a knife this time?
I've got a right to know.
I'm definitely on his list.
- That's not even funny.
- No shit. it's not.
For instance.
I thought I helped my friend
Tyler after his assault.
but now I'm not sure
I helped him enough.
Or if I helped him at all.
Oh. fuck.
No!
Fuck!
Saw that one coming. didn't you?
It's just a drill.
- What if you're wrong?
- I'm not.
- What if it's Tyler?
- It's not.
Because what?
He's better now?
Because it's a drill.
and. yes. he's better.
What reason would he
have to do this again?
Same reason as before.
Me. everyone who treated him
like shit since he was seven.
You of all people should know that.
That shit doesn't just go away.
It haunts you for the
rest of your fucking life...
... which may end today.
Fuck off.
Are you scared?
Are you feeling what terror actually is?
The feeling of sitting here helpless.
and death is on the
other side of that door.
Yes.
- Yes what?
- I'm scared!
Yeah.
I know that feeling.
At the tone. please
record your voice message.
Hey. Mom. it's me. Estela.
I know you're at work.
but... just thought I'd call.
They're doing one of those drills
again. I'm sure it's nothing.
but you always said to call.
I love you...
so much.
Come on.
Jesus. Fuck!
What are you doing?
Code Red.
Shooter. Did you not
hear the announcement?
No.
I was in the darkroom. I had these on.
So...
should we wait to die?
Vicodin. huh?
That's for the car accident?
Uh-huh.
And the vodka?
That's just for fun?
Sorry. I can smell it from here.
Dude. you try walking
around with a broken arm
and a fucked-up knee.
If you keep judging me. I'm
lockin' you back up in your cave.
No. I'm...
not judging.
But maybe you want to try something
that might actually take the pain away.
We're all. like. isolated.
trying to make sense of it.
Trying to hold on.
Can I get my phone?
Sorry. Rob. We need to stay low. okay?
I just wanna text my
parents just to say goodbye.
Hey. None of that.
No goodbyes.
Hey...
don't they usually
tell you in advance...
if it's a drill?
All right. look.
We're all gonna be fine.
We just need to sit
tight till the all-clear.
Or we nut up and bring the hurt
instead of just waiting
around like sitting ducks!
What the fuck are you gonna do?
Swing at the bullets? Don't be stupid.
At least I'm not a coward.
- So you admit to being stupid?
- That's enough!
Just set an example. Both of you.
I take offense to being called stupid
by a recovered addict who still
gets shit-faced at parties.
You fuckin' kidding me?
- Hey. Justin.
- Let's go.
Listen. Justin. Let's go
check the doors in the office.
Maybe we all have that moment of
"what the hell have I done?"
What do you think you're gonna find?
Anything.
Something to tell me
not to lose my shit.
He doesn't want to hurt anyone.
Not anymore. You guys know he's better.
I'm not sure what I know.
Charlie. you and me. we spend
more time with him than anyone.
But didn't something change
after the cops called him in?
What the fuck?
Okay. there's gotta be an
explanation. It's not what we think.
Or it's exactly what we think.
We have to turn these
in and tell someone.
Wait. hold on. We don't
know that this isn't a drill.
Do you really wanna risk that?
If it's real. what good will
it do to turn the photos in?
- You think it'll stop this?
- It might!
There's a chance. If there's a
chance. we gotta do something.
We don't know that it's Tyler.
My dad said he was fine.
Maybe your dad thinks
everything's fine for you.
What does that mean?
That I'm the one who
threw Tyler's guns away.
and if I gave him a second chance.
and he comes in. and he does this...
All right. let's just take a second.
and we can think about
what we need to do.
If you're wrong about
this. his life is over.
If he goes down. how long
do you think it's gonna be
before we all go down too?
Maybe we're all terrified to find out
just what the hell have we done.
Okay.
Do we protect everyone
or just ourselves?
It's a drill.
Can't stop thinkin' about Tyler?
Maybe it's not Tyler.
Maybe it's another kid.
There's. what. 1.000
kids at this school?
You think Tyler's the first
to think about taking a gun
and shooting as many kids as
he could before he died himself?
Nah. I'm still Team Tyler.
No. Tyler's better.
You... you saw that.
I did. but your plan's kinda
falling apart. isn't it?
You don't know what Tyler's up to.
I don't care. It's
not my problem anymore.
It's not your problem?
So you don't think if
someone out there put a gun
to the head of. say. Jessica.
you don't think she'd rat you out?
Oh. or Alex? Or Zach?
Or Justin. Jesus. I bet
he'd piss his little pants.
No. he wouldn't. None of them would.
Okay. what about you? What would
you do with a gun to your head?
I've had a gun to my head.
I've had an AR-15 here.
Right here. and I survived.
and I did the right thing.
'Cause you're Clay
Jensen. You're Liberty High's hero.
You've stared down the
barrel once already.
Hell. you drove off the road
'cause you're not scared
of anything. right?
Are you a hero
or a martyr?
It's just a teacher. checking the locks.
Maybe.
So you're not afraid to die.
just as. like. a general thing?
Maybe I just don't care anymore.
You say that. but
speaking from experience.
you really do 'cause once you're gone.
all that's left is the
shit you didn't do.
Or the shit that you did
do. but you did wrong.
I always tried to do the right thing.
Did you?
If you die today.
is your conscience clear?
I'm not dying today.
No one can ever say that and know.
Fuck.
- Have you been in here the whole time?
- I'm sorry.
I was gonna say something earlier.
but then I heard you
talking on the phone.
and I heard you say your name.
Oh... right.
I'm sorry we haven't
ever. like. officially met.
I was gonna say something. sometime.
but I just didn't know what to say.
It's fine.
I get it.
It's just a drill.
At least that's what I think it is.
Yeah.
It's just...
... this is the last place
in the world I want to be.
Oh...
Everyone's past is the
reason for what they do today.
Hi. Ani.
Hey. it's me. Jess.
Look. I'm sorry I haven't
texted you or called you at all.
I hope your mom's doing okay.
Listen. uh. the night that
you left. you said something.
You said. um...
hating weakness doesn't
make us stronger.
I thought I knew what you meant. but...
... now I don't know.
I was just wondering...
if you meant me?
Sorry. Anyway...
... you don't. um. need to
call me back. I'm being dumb.
I'll talk to you.
I miss you.
Tell your mom I said get well.
Bye.
Dude...
shit's weak.
I don't feel anything.
I expected quality premium
substances from you. Hillcrest boy.
You have eaten
all of the yearbook's snacks.
That's the last of my lunch. so...
... you're stoned.
Mm-mm. You're talking to
the guy that's been fucked up
for half a semester.
I think I'd know if I was...
So why are you always fucked up?
It's fuckin' high school. man.
People suck.
Your friends suck.
I learned that in Burnham Woods.
You talkin' about what
happened with Alex?
You know about it?
Yeah.
So. yeah.
Come to me when your boyfriend
breaks up with you for no reason
and won't even look at ya
and basically hates your guts.
Don't pretend to be innocent. okay?
You lied to him.
How's anybody supposed to believe
you actually gave a shit about Alex?
I do give a shit about Alex.
- I give lots of shits.
- Mm-hmm.
I wasn't playing him.
I loved him.
I still do.
Yeah?
What did you love about him exactly?
He's. like.
the kindest person I've ever met.
Yeah.
Wait.
Are you in love with him too?
No.
But I..
I do love him.
He's a good person. really.
I've done a lot of
fucked-up shit. and...
he never judges me.
You've done some shit?
Like what?
Oh. shit.
Fuck.
Oh. shit. Did you see that?
This isn't a drill.
And we try to clean
up the messes we've made.
He's our friend. Tony.
I know that. Of course I know that.
We all want to protect Tyler
and believe that he's better.
- What if we're wrong?
- Yeah.
What was that?
Oh. shit.
Fuck this. I'm taking this
stuff to Foundry right now.
What... ? No!
Alex. are you okay?
I did this.
Everyone's gonna
die. and it's all my fault.
What? No.
Tony was right. Maybe
we coulda stopped him.
I fu...
I fucked this up like I fuck
up everything!
Alex. hey. listen to me. Listen.
I can't breathe.
I think I'm dying.
Huh? Uh...
Focus on your hands. What do
you feel like? Describe it to me.
I don't fucking know!
Just squeeze my hands.
Okay. you can do that.
Come on. I know you can.
Come on. Alex. Focus on me. Okay?
- Just breathe.
- Okay.
Breathe.
You got it.
It's gonna be okay.
Just breathe.
I think he's gone.
Do you think he'll find us in here?
I don't know.
Sounds like he's moving
away. but if he comes back.
bathroom doors can make great shields.
They're two layers of
a really heavy metal.
We're gonna be fine.
Why would someone do
something like this?
Maybe they're in a lot of pain.
and they think that
this'll make it stop.
Why would hurting
someone else make it stop?
It doesn't.
but you don't know that. You're just...
You're so sad.
and that sadness makes you angry...
all the time.
Like you thought
making a fist would feel good.
and it does.
You feel strong again.
but then you can never...
never unclench that fist.
and you just feel like...
like you just need to hurt someone else.
Did you hurt someone else?
I almost did.
but my friends...
helped me get better.
I'm glad that you didn't do anything.
Me too.
I'm sorry for what
my brother did to you.
everything that you had to go through.
Thank you.
I wonder if Monty could
have gotten better...
if he had the chance.
I guess. yeah.
He fucked up.
but I loved him.
He was lucky to have you for a sister.
It means he had something
good in his life.
Mom. Hi.
Oh. no. Nothing's wrong.
I just. um...
I was on my free period. and
I was just missing you guys.
How's Seattle?
Oh. that's so cool!
I can't wait to visit you guys.
How are Elijah and Cooper?
Oh. my God. You're kidding me?
Can you tell them I love
them... for me. please?
Yeah.
Hey. Mom. um...
I actually have to go now.
Yeah.
I love you.
Okay.
Bye.
Hey. what the hell do you think
you're doin'? Get back in there.
Those were gunshots. We can't sit
here and let people get killed.
Look. that hero talk
ain't worth your lives.
I'm done hiding. and I don't run.
No. see. you fight
as a last resort only.
Now go sit the fuck down.
All right. come on. Diego.
People are scared.
Well. I ain't scared.
I'm ready to fight.
Okay.
Why aren't you. Foley?
You don't want to stand and fight?
You don't even know
where Jessica is. do you?
You're okay to just let her die.
Fuck!
Hey. Okay. enough!
Back in there!
Let's go!
Coach. come on. please! I
don't wanna die like this!
If this is the last day of my life.
I want to be doing the right thing.
It's not gonna be the
last day of anyone's lives.
No one's goin' anywhere. okay?
Okay. everyone. Sit down!
Head count.
Coach...
Foley.
We try to unburden ourselves.
I can't believe I survived
a roll-over crash for this.
Death is playing games with
me. It's just a matter of time.
And no offense. 'cause...
you're actually cooler than I
thought you were gonna be. but...
I don't wanna die with you.
Don't worry.
I don't wanna die with you either.
Jesus.
Jesus!
Listen. if...
if I die and you live...
... will you tell him something for me?
Alex?
Yes.
Will you tell him he's the
first boy I ever truly loved?
Okay.
Yeah. I'll do that.
I beat up Bryce.
What?
The night he died.
I beat him up.
- You killed him?
- No.
No. I went to the police.
They told me that he didn't
die from getting beaten up.
I still feel like shit. though.
That maybe he wouldn't have
died if it wasn't for me.
If I die.
and you live.
would you please...
would you tell Miss
Walker that I'm sorry?
Of course.
Thanks. man.
See? Now that would freak me out.
That sounds like more than just a drill.
Mm. a lot more.
Shut up! Just... just...
just shut up!
Okay. Say it isn't Tyler.
Say it's another kid.
Oh. like little Roddy Corman
who stood up at the assembly.
I don't know why anyone would
want to fuck with that little shit.
- Jesus. you're disgusting.
- Okay. Whatever. Sorry.
It's that sweet. young Roddy.
He just couldn't go on.
Or it's another kid. gets beat at home.
Tryin' to figure out his sexuality.
Angry all the time.
Why aren't you saving him?
Tyler was my friend.
So only your friends
deserve to be saved.
Everyone deserves to be saved.
Then why aren't you saving him?
Then why didn't you save me?
And me?
Now. what happens when one
of those doors opens. Clay?
Some sub didn't know you
need to pull on the door.
so the deadbolt goes
into the strike plate.
Didn't get locked all the way.
Kid gets the door open.
and he sees 20 sophomores
huddled under two tables.
There's nowhere to run.
Sitting ducks.
Fish in a barrel.
You know. he's got a 60-round
magazine and a bump stock.
and they're gone in a minute.
Femoral bleed. hearts burst
by bullets. skulls shattered.
Shut the fuck up! Leave me alone!
Just leave me the fuck alone!
Fuck!
So now 23 kids and a teacher are dead.
She died trying to shield them.
The bullets went right through her.
Clay. that kid.
the kid that you couldn't save.
what happens to him now?
Does he still deserve
to be saved. or should he die?
No one should die.
Before he got to those sophomores
under the table in the room
with the broken door.
before he got there.
- he shot Tony.
- No!
He shot Alex...
he shot Justin.
and you couldn't stop it.
You couldn't save anyone.
I...
I can't save anyone.
I never could.
- And you found this in Tyler Down's bag?
- Yes. sir.
I thought. what if this is him. right?
No. it's good thinking.
No. it's good you brought it to
me. I'll certainly look into this.
Are you going to do something.
like. now. like something?
- Call someone?
- Hush.
I think it's best we handle
it after the lockdown.
But what if there's something
you can do now. and...
There's nothing to be done right now.
- We'll handle it.
- How?
- Fuck.
Thank you. Mr. Padilla. No. stay here.
Gonna wait for the all-clear.
Shit!
Fuck.
Oh. shit. okay.
Hey. hold on! No gun!
Aah!
What the fuck?
Hey.
But sometimes the weight
of what we carry is too much.
That's my dad.
What?
My dad. He's out in the hallway.
I don't... I don't
think anyone's out there.
No. I hear him.
- Alex. Stay down.
- Fuck. I hear him.
No. that's my dad! He's right
out there. Can't you hear him?
He needs to shut up.
- No. it's my dad.
- You two. down. now.
He's calling my name. He's out there.
- Get down.
- I can hear him!
- Tell him to get down.
- Shit. Uh...
Alex. it's the TBI. Okay?
You're not hearing your dad.
It's your brain making
you think you are.
- He's not there. It's the stress.
- No. I hear him.
Alex. it's not him. okay?
It's your mind. Trust me.
Oh.
Come on. Come on. Let's go.
Sometimes it's too much to handle.
What do we do then?
So you still don't care
about anything. Clay?
You still don't have any regrets?
You're glad that I'm dead.
and he got blamed.
- Leave me alone.
- Last day of your life.
No need to keep secrets.
Are you sorry?
Are you sorry for what you did?
Yes.
Yes. I'm sorry.
- Wow.
- I didn't think he'd actually admit it.
We got through to him.
It's too bad you won't live.
but then again. who does?
Blade Runner. Nice.
Well. we only know it 'cause he does.
Am I going crazy?
Asked and answered. no?
Going crazy?
My boy. you done gone.
If there's someone
that needs to be saved.
I'm gonna try to save them.
And if this is the day that I die.
then I die standing up.
Though I still think
it's a fucking drill.
My dad gave me this quote once.
"If you're going through hell.
keep going".
No. no. no! Don't shoot!
Um...
Look. this...
this doesn't have to go this way.
Whatever you've done...
... it can be okay.
Okay? Just...
please don't shoot.
Don't shoot. Please.
I...
Clay! Clay Jensen!
What the hell are you doing?
Clay!
Get in here! Get in here.
Get down.
Is this a drill?
- What were you doin' in that hallway?
- Is this a drill?
- Did you hear the gunshots?
- Yes!
You did.
- So. why did you leave your classroom?
- I thought it was a drill!
Goddamn it. Clay.
This is a hard lockdown.
There were first responders
on the scene with guns drawn.
You thought that was a drill?
Another rule that just
didn't apply to you.
so you thought you'd run
around and be a pain in my ass?
No! Someone kept trying the door.
and I thought someone might need help.
and I didn't want to die sitting down!
Yeah.
- Wait.
- All right. Now listen to me.
No. Look. It's okay.
Clay. you are not gonna die.
You are not gonna die.
The bullets were blanks.
The officers tried the doors.
The alarms were to make sure
that students and
teachers followed protocol.
and the only one who didn't was you.
- They... they pounded at the doors.
- Those were their instructions.
The bullets were blanks?
Simulated gunfire
to make sure the students
will be able to recognize it.
So it was a drill.
Well. if it wasn't.
you'd be dead.
Wait here.
Well. I'm going through hell.
A lot of us are going through hell.
Jess.
that was a fuckin' stapler.
If I had a gun. I would have shot you.
You want to shoot me. don't you?
Deep down. you always have.
Oh. my God.
Justin. you came out of
a window during alockdown.
Who does that?
I...
I was...
We were hiding in the locker room.
and I was just thinking.
what if this is the last
day of our life. you know?
And then I realized...
if this is the last day of my life.
I want to spend it with you.
Okay. uh...
I guess I'll just...
I'll just go back. okay?
Oh. my God. shut the fuck up.
This lockdown is all clear.
I repeat. This lockdown is all clear.
An announcement will be made shortly
to provide staff and students...
Tyler. it's over.
Tyler?
Yeah. that happened to me
before. last year early on. but...
it hadn't happened in a while.
That was the stress.
Yeah. how did you know.
like. what it was?
Uh. I. um..
I googled TBIs a while back.
just to. you know. uh...
know what they entailed.
Like. what you were going through.
Oh. yeah. Um...
Yeah. you know. I'm a freak. so...
No.
No. no. no.
That... was surprising.
Surprising good or surprising bad?
Well. you two recovered.
Kind of.
- What?
- Well. I shoulda seen that comin'.
Wait. what did Foundry say?
He. uh. said he was gonna look into it.
and then he said he
heard from the office
that this was just a fucking drill.
Okay. so if the cops bring him in again.
what is that gonna mean for us?
Hey. listen.
What I said earlier. about
what happened with Bryce.
I was super out of it.
And even though you
didn't kill Bryce that night.
you don't want to be known as the guy
who beat the shit out of
him before he died. right?
Yeah.
Exactly.
Don't worry.
I can keep a secret.
Thanks. man.
Sure.
Except. here's the thing.
If you know for a fact
you didn't kill Bryce.
then you must know who did. right?
- Fantastic job.
- Thanks.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you. sir.
Gentlemen. thank you for
your expertise. for your training.
A lot of us are going through hell...
I understand this is not easy...
... and I don't know how we keep going.
You made a big difference today.
What the fuck?
What the actual fuck are you thinking?
Clay. would you take a
seat in my office. please?
No! I will not take
a seat in your office!
You think that this is
the way to make us safe?
You know what would make me feel safe?
Not having to go to a
school with metal detectors
or video cameras or
armed fucking guards!
There's still class. folks.
Okay? Bell has not rung.
No. you're killing us!
You are killing us! Don't you get that?
You made a drill with gunshots
and hammered down the door
to prepare us for what exactly?
What it feels like to be hunted?
To practice getting ready to die.
to make us feel afraid for our lives?
We already know how that feels!
You're scaring us to death!
- Every day! Every day! Every day!
- Calm down. son.
I am not your goddamn son!
Get the fuck away from me!
We are children!
We're kids! We should be
living our fucking lives
instead of practicing how to cheat
death. because you know what?
Everybody fucking dies!
Everybody dies!
So. please. please let us live!
We are trying to keep you alive.
That's what every minute of
this drill has been about.
No! It was about you checking
a fucking box. a regulation.
a law. whatever the fuck.
because you know what?
- You know what? We're not safe.
- That's enough.
Hey. fuck you. "that's
enough". Who are you?
Who are you to say it's enough?
Who are you?
Clay! Stop!
- Clay!
- Am I safer now?
Huh? I've got your gun! I've
got your gun! Am I safer?
- Please.
- Look at me. I'm armed.
Should I give this to a teacher
so they can save their fucking class?
Clay. please.
Put the gun down.
We'll go to my office.
and we will talk this over. okay?
Come on.
Tyler...
what happened to us?
What did you do?
I didn't do anything.
Okay. Okay.
- No!
- Hey!
Get off me! Get off of me now!
No!
No. please!
No! God. no!
- No!
- No...
Well done. Ed. Well done.
- Synced and corrected by Firefly -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today